# **Brice Shatzer**

www.BriceShatzer.com

brice.shatzer@gmail.com 319-239-2470

Chicago-based technologist with over a decade of experience building software for businesses of all sizes. Skilled in crafting both delightful user-facing interactions & pragmatic solutions, with a passion for the administrative and organizational processes around the craft of software development.

#### Tools & Technologies -

- "Vanilla" HTML, CSS, & JavaScript
- JavaScript Typescript / Flow
   React / Preact / Svelte / Storybook.js
- **Node.js** *Next.js / Express.js*
- CSS SASS/SCSS/LESS

*TailwindCSS / styled-components* 

- Build Tools Webpack / Babel / Rollup / Vite
  Gulp / Grunt / ESLint / Prettier / PostCSS
- Testing Jest / Mocha / Jasmine / Enzyme / Karma Puppeteer / BrowserStack / LambdaTest
- CI/CD GitHub Actions / CircleCl / Bitbucket
- AWS EC2 / S3 / Lambda / DynamoDB

#### Recent Work Experience

#### **Senior Software Engineer** – W.W. Grainger, Inc.

October 2021 - September 2024

- Part of the Core Engineering team that was responsible for building, documenting, & supporting the design system and various other tools that are relied upon by various teams across the 1000+ person engineering organization. This team was responsible for saving over 5400 hours of engineering work during my tenure
- · Worked primarily in React, Svelte, Next.js, & styled-components

#### **Senior Software Engineer** – PayPal

July 2020 - August 2021

- Part of the Checkout Integrations team that worked on the company's flagship service which handles \$100+B in payment volumes across 200+ countries for millions of active users a month
- Developed critical "Pay w/ Venmo" desktop solution, enabling seamless cross-platform payment experiences for customers and unlocking an entirely new payment source for vendors
- Wrote, curated, and published comprehensive documentation around the various tools, libraries, & SDKs that are both used internally and made available to the open source community
- Worked primarily in Preact, Flow, Storybook.js & Express

# **Software Engineer** – Onion Inc. | G/O Media

September 2017 - April 2020

- Part of the team that worked on Kinja, the CMS powering some of the internet's favorite sites like Gizmodo, Lifehacker, Kotaku, and The Onion; reaching 85-100 million active users a month
- Helped migrate and rewrite our core platform from a Scala w/ Closure templates & Backbone.js to an Isomorphic JavaScript (Express & React) solution

#### Full Work History

# **Software Engineer**

February 2016 - April 2017

Doejo – Digital agency that specialized in serving enterprise WordPress VIP clients

### Web Developer II

September 2015 - February 2016

GoHealth - One of the leading digital health insurance marketplaces

# **UI/Front-End Developer**

November 2014 - September 2015

Packback – SharkTank-funded startup creating a platform for digital textbook rentals

# Web Developer/Designer

April 2012 - July 2014

Links Technology Solutions — Agency providing custom web & software solutions

#### Education